# Zubair Ashfaque

### Data Scientist / Machine Learning Engineer

System Analyst with 6+ years of experience in several industries. My journey from internet networks to neural networks is driven by my passion to learn. Looking to leverage my experience and knowledge as a Data Scientist or Machine learning engineer at your company.



mianashfaque@gmail.com

O Lahore, Pakistan

in linkedin.com/in/zubair-ashfaque-ab100621

+923018480350

zubairashfaque.github.io/

🌎 github.com/zubairashfaque

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **System Analyst**

Jazz

07/2017 - Present

Jazz is a Pakistani mobile network and internet services provider

Lahore

#### Task

- I worked as a System Analyst in the revenue assurance department, I balanced a swath of competing priorities, ranging from daily ETL operations tasks and automation of alerts to fixing problems, incorporation new business controls, and developing new APIs.
- This role helped me to develop a wide-range understanding of telco fraud and revenue controls, improving my programming skills, planning skills, and debugging skills. It also gave me a chance to work on new technologies like HADOOP.

Contact: Muhammad Faizan Anwar - faizan.anwar@jazz.com.pk

# Enterprise Application Integration (EAI) Planning Jazz

01/2012 - 07/2017

Tasks

 Design, implementation, deployment, and maintenance of middleware architecture integrated with CRM (Siebel), Electronic Financial Inventory Control System (EFICS), Billing System (Geneva) and Provisioning System (Comptel).

Contact: Jalal Shahid - jalal.shahid@quest.jazz.com.pk

# Broadband Supervisor

PTCL

009 - 2011 Lai

PTCL provides telephone and internet services nationwide and is the backbone for the country's telecommunication infrastructure

#### Tasks

 Configuring different ADSL routers & modems solving different problems regarding DSL and IPTV. Additional task was to develop and maintain the database of BCMS which was a complaint management system.

# **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor in Telecom Systems**Beaconhouse National University

2005 - 2009

## **PROGRAMMING & SOFTWARE**

Python

PySpark

SQL

Apache Spark

TensorFlow

Tableau

Pytorch

**HADOOP** 

Keras C

# **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

A Network Analysis of Game of Thrones 🗹

In project analyze the network of characters in Game of Thrones and how it changes over the course of the books.

Universities Admission Prediction Using Multiple Linear Regression ♂

Predicting Universities Admission Using Multiple Linear Regression

Detecting Fake News with Machine Learning

Detecting Fake News with NLP Machine Learning

Visit San Francisco: What To See, Where To Stay & Where To Eat  $\ensuremath{\ensuremath{\text{C}}}$ 

SAN FRANCISCO'S VENUES RECOMMENDATION MAPS

Predict Numbers from Handwritten Digits 🗹

Predict Numbers from Handwritten Digits using a Neural Network

Twitter Sentiment Analysis 🗹

Using Naive Bayes classifier to predict sentiment from thousands of Twitter tweets.

# PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATE

TENSORFLOW DEVELOPER CERTIFICATE (10/2020 - Present)

♂

Tensorflow.org

- Using TensorFlow to solve deep learning and ML problems.
- TensorFlow Certificate Network

GCP (06/2020 - Present) 🛂

google

Google Cloud Platform Badges

IBM (01/2019 - Present) 🗗

Coursera

• IBM data science professional certificate

# **LANGUAGES**

Language

Full Professional Proficiency